Harin Lee

www.harinlee.info hlee@cbs.mpg.de

PhD candidate in Cognitive Science

GitHub: harin-git Twitter: TweetHarin

My research interests are about the cross-cultural diversity in music and the methods we can apply to quantify its characteristics. I combine datasets of music around the world with large-scale behavioural experiments to tackle questions about inter-individual and cross-cultural differences in music cognition.

EDUCATION

PhD fellowship at IMPRS NeuroCom

Oct 2020 — Present

Max Planck Institute for Human Cognitive and Brain Sciences

Leipzig, Germany

· Neurobiology group led by Prof. Marc Schönwiesner

Visiting researcher

Oct 2020 — Present

Max Planck Institute for Empirical Aesthetics

Frankfurt, Germany

• Computational Auditory Perception group led by Dr. Nori Jacoby

MSc in Music, Mind and Brain (Distinction)

Oct 2017 — Oct 2-18

Goldsmiths, University of London

London, UK

• Thesis titled "Signals through music and dance: Perceived social bonds and formidability in synchronised and coordinated movements" — supervised by Prof. Lauren Stewart and Dr. Jacques Launay

BMus in Popular Music Studies (First class honour)

Oct 2013 — Jun 2017

Goldsmiths, University of London

London, UK

 Research project titled "Research project: Production of an album consisting of five compositions written in a novel musical scale developed using MaxMSP"

A-Levels Oct 2011 — Jun 2013
Richard Huish College Taunton, UK

• A* A* A in Math, Music technology, Physics

PUBLICATIONS

- Anglada-Tort, M., Lee, H., Krause, A. E., & North, A. C. (2023). Here comes the sun: Music features of popular songs reflect prevailing weather conditions. *Royal Society Open Science*, 10(5), 221443. https://doi.org/10.1098/rsos.221443
- van Rijn, P., Sun, Y., Lee, H., Marjieh, R., Sucholutsky, I., Lanzarini, F., André, E., & Jacoby, N. (2023). Around the world in 60 words:
 A generative vocabulary test for online research. *Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society*.
 https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2302.01614
- Anglada-Tort, M., Harrison, P. M. C., Lee, H., & Jacoby, N. (2023). Large-scale iterated singing experiments reveal oral transmission mechanisms underlying music evolution. *Current Biology*, 0(0). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2023.02.070
- Marjieh, R., Rijn, P. V., Sucholutsky, I., Sumers, T., Lee, H., Griffiths, T. L., & Jacoby, N. (2023). Words are all you need? Language as an approximation for human similarity judgments. *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*. https://arxiv.org/abs/2206.04105
- van Rijn, P., Lee, H. (shared co-first), & Jacoby, N. (2022). Bridging the prosody GAP: Genetic Algorithm with People to efficiently sample emotional prosody. *Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society*. 10.5281/zenodo.5625680
- Lee, H., Hoeger, F., Schoenwiesner, M., Park, M., & Jacoby, N. (2021). Cross-cultural Mood Perception in Pop Songs and its Alignment with Mood Detection Algorithms. *Proceedings of the 22nd International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR)*, 366–373. https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5625680
- Lee, H., Launay, J., & Stewart, L. (2020). Signals through music and dance: Perceived social bonds and formidability on collective movement. *Acta Psychologica*, 208, 103093. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2020.103093
- Lee, H., & Müllensiefen, D. (2020). The Timbre Perception Test (TPT): A new interactive musical assessment tool to measure timbre perception ability. *Attention, Perception, and Psychophysics*, 82(7), 3658–3675.
 https://doi.org/10.3758/s13414-020-02058-3

IN-REVIEW

• Marjieh, R., Harrison, P. M. C., Lee, H., Deligiannaki, F., & Jacoby, N. Reshaping musical consonance with timbral manipulations and massive online experiments. *In review*. https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2022.06.14.496070v1

SKILLS

Tools and Code Quantitative Research Languages R, Python, Git, धाट्स, MarkDown, MaxMSP, Ableton, 3D Motion Capture
Large-scale automated online experiments (PsyNet, Dallinger), Reproducible Science
English, Korean

Harin Lee

GitHub: harin-git

Graz, Austria

2016 - 2018

Twitter: TweetHarin

www.harinlee.info hlee@cbs.mpg.de

PhD candidate in Cognitive Science

Presentations	
Cultural Evolution Society (CES)	2022
(Oral) Studying the evolution of pop music across 55 countries since the 1950s	Aarhus, Denmark
Systematic Musicology (SysMus)	2022
(Oral) Song Lyrics Around the World	Ghent, Belgiun
Cognitive Science Society Annual Meeting (CogSci)	2022
(Oral & Poster) Bridging the prosody GAP: Genetic Algorithm with People to efficiently sample emotional prosod	•
22nd International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR)	2021
(Oral, nominated for Best Student Paper) Cross-cultural mood perception in pop songs and its alignment with n algorithms	nooa aetection Virtua
16th International Conference on Music Perception and Cognition (ICMPC)	2021
(Oral, nominated for Best Student Paper) Converging and diverging patterns in the evolution of popular music as	
Timbre2020	2020 2020
(Poster) A New Test for Measuring Individual's Timbre Perception Ability	Virtua
Conference on Interdisciplinary Musicology Embodiment Music	2019
(Oral) A New Test for Measuring Individual's Timbre Perception Ability	Graz, Austric
Forum IRCAM Annual Workshop	2019
(Poster) TPT: Timbre Perception Test	Paris, France
Invited Talks	,
	2021
CompMusic Lab, Keio University Cross-cultural mood perception in pop songs and its alignment with algorithmic estimates	2022 Virtua
	2022
Deezer, Paris GlobalPOP: Investigating the historical trajectories of popular music around the world	Virtua
Brain Awareness Week Science Night	2022
Without a song or a dance what are we?	Leipzig, Germany
	Leipzig, Germany
Professional Experiences	
Intern Scientific Researcher, Deezer (Paris)	2023 — current
Co-founder, "aiar" neuro-music collective (aiarcollective. com) (Leipzig)	since 2021
Research Assistant, Music Technology and Wearables X-SYSTEM Ltd. (London) Producer and Sound Engineer, CMS studie (London), Part time D. L. Music Producer.	2018 2014 — 2018
Producer and Sound Engineer, GMS studio (London), Part-time DJ, Music Producer	2014 — 2018
GRANT & FELLOWSHIPS	
Diverse Intelligence Summer Institute (DISI) research fellow (\$3,000)	2022
3-weeks long summer school	St. Andrews, Scotland
Art project funded by the Leipzig City Council (€9,500)	2022
An installation piece incorporating live brain imaging to shape musical soundscapes	Leipzig, Germany
PhD research fellow funded by the Max Planck Society (3 years full funding)	2020
Awarded on competitive basis	Germany
Academic Excellence Scholarship (£3,000) Awarded to enter the MSc course	201 7 <i>Uk</i>
Joe Brown Memorial Scholarship (£500)	2016
Awarded for creative project involving live electronic work during BMus	Ur
OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS	
Neuromatch Academy Summer School	2020
Completed 3-weeks interactive track on computational neuroscience	Virtua
Open Research Software and Open Source certificate Open Science MOOC	2019
Technical Team	2018

ICMPC15/ESCOM10 — Largest conference on music cognition

Performed at the Horniman Museum and PureGold Festival 2018

Goldsmiths Balinese Gamelan Group